AMELINE NUSSBAUMER

Learning & Digital Content Creator -

www.linkedin.com/tin/amelinenussbaumer

amelinenussbaumer.github.io



in

ameline.nussbaumer@gmail.com

7 rue des Bosquets 68 130 Altkirch France

+33 7 69 75 76 08



PROFILE

Autonomous and flexible professional with 10 years' experience managing online and blended learning projects for international organisations. Strong experience in the design and production of interactive learning resources, engaging communication visuals and change materials. Efficient team player comfortable with remote project management and multi-cultural contexts.

EDUCATION

MSc in Comparative and International Education

University of Oxford | UK 2013 - 2014

BA (Hons) in Education and Modern Languages

University of Cambridge | UK 2008 - 2012

IT SKILLS

- Authoring Tools (Adobe Captivate, Articulate Storyline, Elucidat, BranchTrack, Vyond, Mohive)
- LMS (CrossKnowledge, Docebo, Moodle)
- Graphic design (Adobe Suite, Canva)
- Information Management (Office, Slack, Trello, Jive)
- Communications (Hootsuite)

LANGUAGES

- French (mothertongue)
- English (bilingual)
- German (working proficiency)
- Spanish (basic)

REFERENCE

Alain Court

Head of Learning Solutions Unit, ICRC acourt@icrc.org

+41 22 730 34 93

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Digital Learning Consultant

10.2020 - Current

I design, produce, and deliver learning experiences to meet customer needs and objectives. This includes instructional design, course production, and, when required, the creation of the learning path on the LMS platform.

Consultancies with UN Global Compact Foundation, UNECE, and the ICRC, with track-record of always delivering on time

• Designed training paths on diverse topics for large audiences (including all-staff compliance training)

Produced branching scenarios and rapid learning modules to create engaging and practice-oriented content for learners

A Rocha Kenya (Conservation NGO) | Watamu, KE

Communications and Fundraising Officer | 01.2020 - 08.2020

Field experience during which I was responsible for fundraising, communication, and local capacity-building initiatives.

- Led international grant applications and crowdfunding campaigns
- Managed external communication: website, social media channels, annual report, newsletter, etc.

International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) | Geneva, CH

Techno-Pedagogical Engineer | 07.2016 - 12.2019

I managed learning initiatives liaising with internal experts and external providers. As Applications Trainer, I produced online learning courses, conducted trainings of trainers to build internal training capacity, and supported the digital transformation of the division.

- Managed the design and development of trainings in various formats: eLearning, blended, mobile app, face-to-face
- Produced user-friendly learning resources to facilitate colleagues' adoption and use of new digital tools
- Delivered training of trainers and regular internal workshops on training practices and digital tools
- Designed and facilitated online communities of practice and online learning paths

UN Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR) | Geneva, CH

E-learning Officer | 09.2014 - 06.2016

I gained experience in the development, promotion and evaluation of online courses, along with project management and communication skills.

- Facilitated, translated, and evaluated eLearning courses on Moodle
- Co-organized an international Forum (logistics and content)